Ruben A. Sanchez

Researcher experienced in data analysis, behavioral research, clinical diagnostics, and patient care.

Experience

2023 Scholar Yale Biological and Biomedical Sciences

Accepted into and completed the Science Communication Training Series.

2021 to 2022 Tutor Independent

Tutored international students in English composition.

2020 Academic Success Mentor Independent

Served as advisor for student at risk of losing residency due to academic standing.

· Student successfully completed previously failed courses and graduated.

2019 Co-Author Peer Reviewed Journal

Zyzik, E.C., & Sanchez, R.A. (2019). Beyond accuracy: Heritage speakers' performance on two kinds of

acceptability judgment tasks. Applied Psycholinguistics, 40(3), 645-671.

2018 to 2019 Lead Associate Macv's Fine Jewelry

Scheduled employee shifts, trained staff, resolved interpersonal conflicts, coordinated events, facilitated

team building exercises, administered one on one coaching sessions, and motivated team.

Data Analyst Bilingualism Research Lab at U.C.S.C. 2017 to 2018

Prepared data, designed quality control measures, conducted statistical exploratory analysis and inferential

analysis. Communicated findings by constructing data visualizations and writing reports.

2016 Annotator Natural Language & Dialogue Systems Lab at U.C.S.C.

Annotated social media content for computational modeling via language entrainment and narrative

summarizations.

Research Assistant Cognitive Science U.C.S.C. 2014

Coded acoustic data with Praat and video data with After Effects.

2012 Research Assistant Linguistics U.C.S.C.

Developed and implemented a phonological study. Designed and prepared stimuli, recruited and scheduled

participants, ran study, as well as analyzed and reported data.

Education

2015 **B.S.** Cognitive Science University of California, Santa Cruz **B.A.** Linguistics 2015 University of California, Santa Cruz

Pre Academia

Technical Assistant Pfizer Global Research & Development Performed health observations and animal husbandry. Animal Technician The Scripps Research Institute Learned tumor measurements and peritoneal injections. Quest Diagnostics **Acting Coordinator** Described clinical procedures and laboratory results. Medical Assistant

Sharp Vitals, immunizations, and assisted in minor surgery.

Summary of Qualifications

Programming Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, GIT, Bash

Research E-Prime, SuperLab, Praat, Audacity, ELAN, SPSS, Mendeley, Zotero, Qualtrics, Tableau, Power BI

Design Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Figma, Invision, Blender Documentation Access, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Sheets, Docs, Slides, LaTeX

Project Management, Team Building, Issue Resolution Leadership

Qualities Empathy, Patience, Curiosity, Drive

Clinical Medical Terminology, HIPAA, Triage, UAs, Phlebotomy, Injections, ECG, Spirometry, History & Physical

Languages High proficiency in English, Italian, and Spanish. Learning Japanese.

Previous Certifications Registered Medical Assistant (AMT), First Responder BLS (ARC)